Furman Przemek

+31 6 48454578 | furmanp@proton.me

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

Core Competencies: TypeScript • JavaScript • Node.JS Express.JS • HTML • CSS ORM • REST API • SCRUM

Additional Knowledge: VB.NET • Python • Postman

PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

Good time management Ability to perform under pressure Prototyping and troubleshooting skills

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY

AUTOMATION CONTROL AND ROBOTICS

Msc. Engineering

2011 - 2017 | Warsaw, Poland

UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY

MECHANICAL ENGINEERING ERASMUS STUDENT EXCHANGE 2015 - 2016 | Dresden, Germany

LINKS

Github:// furmanp LinkedIn:// Przemek Furman

ABOUT ME

Graduate of faculty of Mechatronics with seven years of experience in field of mechanical engineering, specializing in high-performant composite structures. In 2020 introduced automation into design and simulation workflows using VB.NET and Python into the company. Decided to entirely transition to software engineering in 2022. Currently developing a web applications for offshore industry. Highly motivated both professionally and privately.

EXPERIENCE

TEMPORARY WORKS DESIGN | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

September 2022 - Present | Rotterdam Stack: TypeScript, React, VB.NET, Node.JS, Express, HTML5, CSS

- Responsible for development of web applications automating naval and mechanical calculations.
- Contributed to the development of automation tools used internally to improve design processes.
- Leading the development of tool to streamline deck layout arrangements for offshore operations.
- Participating in development of design and business side of products.
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams to ensure alignment with user requirements.

VISOFT | FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

February 2024 – Present | Part-time | Amsterdam Stack: TypeScript, Qwik, SurrealDB, GraphQL, Moralis

- Development of Automated Porftolio Management solution for web3.
- Querying blockchain data. Combining data in charts.
- Triggering rebalancing, batch transactions.

PONTIS ENGINEERING | DESIGN ENGINEER | SOFTWARE CONSULTANT

January 2020 – August 2022 / March 2024 - Present | Amsterdam Stack: VB.NET, Python

- Developed set of tools to automate Structural Simulations for Composite materials.
- Developed office automation tools that became company standard.
- Initiated and introduced centralised codebase, VCS, entirely documented codebase and set up online documentation.
- Currently providing external support in the area of automation and software development.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

AUTODESK PLATFORM SERVICES ACCELERATOR PROGRAM | TWD

March 2023 | Copenhagen, Denmark June 2024 | London, England

TOP PERFORMER | PONTIS ENGINEERING

January 2022 | Amsterdam